Q Profile

A Computer Games Techonology graduate with a passion for technology. My biggest strengths are my communication and organisational skills. Founder and president of a computing society at Birmingham City University, organised numerous hackathons and completed a one year work placement working for Birmingham City University.

Employment

September 2016 - present

Technical Demonstrator - Birmingham City University

Role description:

• Aid students during lab programming activities

August 2015 - August 2016

Computer Science Placement Student - Birmingham City University

Role description:

- Created effective software for demonstration purposes
- Successfully organised BCUHack Birmingham City University's first 24 hour hackathon
- Co-authored a research paper on hackathons
- Successfully coordinated applicant visit days for the university
- Excelled as an in-class demonstrator and invigilator on exams

July 2015 - August 2015

IT Intern - Postbank, Bulgaria

June 2014 - August 2014

Barman/Waiter - Hotel Sunny, Bulgaria

November 2013 - December 2013

Paid Fundraiser - HOME Fundraising, UK

August 2012 - September 2012

Web Data Entry - WebFactory, Bulgaria

P Achievements

- FrontRunners Leadership Training
- HackNotts Best Use of Just Giving API
- Regular Hackathon attendee and organiser
- President and Founder of the Hackathon and Computing Society at BCU
- President and Founder of the Game Development Club at ACS

Languages

- English Fluent
- German Fluent
- Bulgarian Fluent
- Spanish Basic

Education

2013 - Present - Birmingham City University

BSc(Hons) Computer Games Technology - 1st class

2008 - 2013 - American College of Sofia

American Diploma and Bulgarian Diploma (5.32/6) with a Programming Focus

2005 - 2008 - Uwekind International School, Sofia

Technical Skills

- Game Development Unity, Irrlicht, DirectX
 ★★★★
- Programming (OOP) C++, C#, Python
 ★★★☆
- Web Development JavaScript, HTML, Node.js
 ★★☆☆
- Open Systems, Networking, Microcontrollers
 ★★☆☆

Personal Skills

- Leadership I have always lead or strived to lead any team that I have worked in, a very useful skill during my time as president of the Hackathon and Computing Society.
- Communication I am able to speak directly to people and use this to achieve results, a very useful skill when aiding students or organising events.
- Event Organization I have experience with organising multiple hackathons (BCUHack, Hack-TheMidlands, LocalHackDay '16, BullHacks), as well as smaller events.
- Public Speaking I am confident speaking in front of people and clearly communicating my message.

Interests

- Environmental Preservation
- Travelling
- Cooking
- Art

Contact

- f OV Games
- in Oliver Vlaytchev
- @olivlaytchev
- olivlaytchev
- **** +447908143701
- olivlaytchev@yahoo.co.uk